你不应该搅和进来的  罗伊
You should've stayed out of this, Royce.
你根本就不知道
You have no idea
你自己马上就要下地狱了
the hell that's about to rain down on you.
好怕哦
Scary.
他在哪
Where is he?
转身回家  让我来处理这个  好吗
Turn around and go back home and let me handle this, all right?
长官  我又不是第一次见尸体
Sir, I've seen dead bodies before.
别倔啊  凯特  看到他的尸体你只会更伤心
Come on, Kate. You don't want to remember him like this.
卡塞尔  如果死的人是我  你会转身走开吗
Castle, if it was me lying there, would you just walk away?
我很遗憾  亲爱的
I'm so sorry, honey.
告诉我发生什么了
So tell me what happened.
他腿部中弹
He was shot in the leg.
从血迹判断
Judging from the blood trail,
我判断子弹打碎了骨头
I'd say the bullet broke the bone.
他试着躲避  但是
He tried to hide, but...
我在他口袋中找到了这个
Uh, I found this in his pocket.
他今天下午刚刚从洛杉矶飞来
He just flew in from Los Angeles this afternoon.
他去洛杉矶干什么
What was he doing in L.A.?
我听说他丢了赏金猎人的执照后就搬到了那里
I heard he moved there after he lost his bounty hunter's license.
我猜他是想试着重新开始
I guess he was trying to make a fresh start.
你最后一次和他说话是什么时候
When was the last time you spoke to him?
我逮捕他的时候
When I arrested him.
蕾妮  我能看看他吗
Lanie, could I?
当然
Sure.
罗伊
Royce, um...
他的口袋里还有些东西
had something else in his pocket.
是写给你的
It's addressed to you.
和案子有关的
About the case?
不是
No.
我们好像找到了凶器
Think we got the murder weapon.
在街角的垃圾桶里找到的
Found it in the garbage around the corner.
这把枪最近绝对开过火
Gun was definitely fired recently.
凶手在弃枪之前清空了子弹
Shooter took the time to empty the ammo before he dumped it.
担心我们会在子弹上找到指纹吗
Worried we'd find fingerprints on the bullets?
这是把便宜的街头手枪  垃圾货
This is a cheap street gun. It's a throwaway.
枪管上有螺纹
There's threading on the barrel.
-消声器  -对
- Silencer? - Yeah.
使得凶手可以在光天化日之下射杀罗伊
Allowing our killer to shoot Royce in broad daylight.
听着  贝克特  我们会将凶手缉拿归案的
Listen, Beckett, we're gonna get this guy.
已经派警员去调查
We got uniforms hitting
五个街区范围内的每一个商店和公寓
every store and apartment in a 5-block radius.
纽约这种大城市人来人往  肯定会有目击证人的
This is New York. Somebody had to have seen something.
从洛杉矶到纽约
L.A. to New York
罗伊似乎在躲避什么
It's like royce was running from something,
好像他知道自己身处险境
Like he knew he was in danger.
关于消音器你说对了
You were right about the silencer.
实验室在螺纹中发现了钛合金
The lab found trace amounts of titanium alloy in the threads.
他们将范围缩小到两种商业消音器之一
They've narrowed it done to one of two commercial suppressors.
每种价格都约一千美元
Both run about a grand.
为什么把这么贵的消音器安在一把烂枪上
Why put an expensive silencer on a cheap gun?
因为凶手从洛杉矶跟随罗伊至此
Because our killer followed Royce from l.A.
他没办法把自己的枪带上飞机
and couldn't bring his own gun on the plane.
而消音器只是个圆筒
But a silencer is just a cylinder.
要藏在托运行李里轻而易举
It could easily be hidden in a checked bag.
筛选出所有
Isolate all of the flights
凶手可能从洛杉矶跟随罗伊至此的班机
that someone could've followed Royce from L.A. on.
数量不会有很多  特别是
There couldn't have been that many, and specifically,
要注意那些在最后时刻买票的人
focus on the people who might have bought tickets last minute.
好的
Right.
你究竟卷入了什么阴谋  迈克
What the hell were you into, Mike?
我们查到  有5列从洛杉矶起飞的航班符合条件
Okay, so we got five flights out of L.A. that meet our criteria.
我调查了所有的乘客
I ran all the passengers,
一个名字跳了出来
and one name popped.
尼尔·麦考利在起飞前一小时到机场买了票
Neel McCauley bought his ticket at the airport an hour before the flight
而他的身份却是一段查无此证的崭新历史
His identity is brand-new-no credit history,
他的驾照号码也是假的
and his driver's license number is a fake.
尼尔·麦考利  真的假的
Neel McCauley, really?
怎么了
Why?
那是罗伯特·德尼罗在《盗火线》中的角色名
That's Robert De Niro's character in "Heat".
他就是我们要找的家伙
That's our guy.
好吧  要真是的话  你就要登机了
Well, if it is, you're gonna need to get on a plane,
因为麦考利先生已经飞回了洛杉矶
'cause Mr. McCauley flew back to L.A.
起飞时间恰好是罗伊遇害2小时后
two hours after Royce was shot.
我不会派你去洛杉矶的  你没有确凿的证据
I'm not sending you to L.A. You have no solid evidence
证明尼尔·麦考利和此谋杀案有关
linking Neel McCauley to this murder.
他来纽约待了六个小时
He came to New York for six hours.
谁会飞过来就待那么短的时间
Who flies in for that short a stay?
商人常常在各地短暂停留
Businessmen do it all the time.
商人可不会使用假身份
Businessmen don't use false I.D.s...
也不会带着消音器吧
Or pack a silencer.
那只是猜想  我需要更有说服力的证据
That's supposition. I need a lot more than that
才能派一个探长名正言顺地跨城市查案
to justify flying a detective across the country.
你我都清楚我等的时间越长
You and I both know that the longer I wait to go out there,
破案就越难
the colder this trail gets.
你休一天假  好好冷静一下
Take a day, shore this up,
如果证据充足  我会联系洛杉矶警局
and if there's sufficient evidence, i'll contact L.A.P.D.
你会联系洛杉矶警局
You'll contact the L.A.P.D.?
这是我的案子  这发生在我们的辖区里
This is my case. This happened in our jurisdiction.
你觉得洛杉矶警局会出手相助吗
You think the L.A.P.D. is gonna lift a finger
凯特  你和此案牵扯太深
Kate, you're too close to this.
不  长官  我尽职尽责  不会因私情妨碍公务的
No, sir, I am committed. I am not compromised.
你心力交瘁
You're torn up!
凯特  你和罗伊的关系结束的很糟糕
Kate, things between you and Royce ended badly.
我理解  但正是因为你的这种情绪
I get it, but that emotion is exactly why
我才要把调查工作交给别人
I need to assign this to someone else.
或许你说得对
You know what? You're right.
我和此案牵扯太深
I am too close to this.
我正好有几个假期没有休
I have some vacation days coming up.
我觉得现在正是时候
I think now would be a good time.
凯特
Kate.
我希望你不要鲁莽行事
I hope you're not thinking about doing something reckless.
不会的  长官
No, sir.
你去哪儿
Where you going?
-回家  -骗谁呢
- Home. - The hell you are.
卡塞尔  拜托
Castle... Please.
他是我的训练官  我的朋友
He was mtraining officer, my friend.
我只是  我现在真的需要一个人呆一会儿
I just... I really need to be alone right now.
亲爱的凯特
Dear Kate,
恐怕我已千百次提笔写这封信
I bet I've written this letter a hundred times.
或许有一天  我真会把它寄出去
Someday, I might actually send it.
对于我所做的一切都没有借口
There's no excuse for what I did,
特别是我对你所做的一切
Especially what I did to you.
但是我已经走上正道了
But I'm on a righteous path now.
我希望能有一天
And I hope someday,
这条正道能让我得到你的原谅
that path earns me your forgiveness.
-不好意思  贝克特探长吗  -是的
- Excuse me. Detective beckett?  - Yes.
你已经被升到头等舱了
You've been upgraded to first class.
对不起  借过
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
不好意思
Sorry about that.
座位号3C
Seat 3-C.
谢谢
Thank you.
来杯香槟吗
Champagne?
《灵书妙探》第三季第22集
集名《To Love and Die in L.A》
翻译：千花  旺妹  媛媛  DJ  LyraL  米苏  思无邪  irene
时间轴：Jimmybeck   好油油    校对：大卫熊   后期&总监：瓜瓜
卡塞尔  你跟来干什么
Castle, what are you doing?
制作公司已经催了我几个礼拜了
Oh, the studio's been after me for weeks
让我飞去电影版《希特热浪》的片场探班
To fly down and do a set visit for the "Heat wave" Movie.
看到你名字也在同一架班机上  我惊讶半天呢
Imagine my surprise when I saw your name on the standby list.
我将要做的事  你不准掺和
You cannot be a part of what I'm gonna do out there.
我以为你是去度假呢
I thought you were on vacation.
卡塞尔
Castle...
在纽约办案  你跟着我是一回事
It is one thing for you to follow me when we're in New York,
但我在洛杉矶可不是警察
but I am not a cop in L.A.
没有任何职权  也无后援
I don't have any authority or backup.
我来当你的后援
I'll be your backup.
再说了  当一介草民可是我的专长啊
Besides, going rogue is kind of my specialty.
是啊  但你做事从来不懂看人脸色
Yeah, but subtlety isn't.
我是甩不掉你了  是吧
I'm not gonna get rid of you, am I?
好吧  听着
Okay, look...
如果我们要共事  你一定要向我保证
If we do this together, you have to promise me
我们一定要低调
that we're gonna fly under the radar.
当然了
Of course.
这也叫低调吗
Is this what you call "Under the radar"?
在洛杉矶  小跑车就是主流啊
In L.A., this baby fits right in.
我们第一站去哪儿
So what's our first stop?
我的宾馆  在万特乐大道
My hotel. It's on Ventura Blvd.
那要一直到山谷那里
That's all the way in the Valley.
你离我那么远  我们怎么一起行动
How are we supposed to work together if you're an hour away?
卡塞尔  我们完全没必要一起行动
Castle, we weren't supposed to work together at all.
好吧  听着
Okay, look,
制作公司给我免费提供了一间四星级的双人套房
the studio comped me a two-bedroom, four-star suite.
-你跟着我就行了  -是啊  没错
- You just stay with me. - Yeah, right.
怎么了  你会有自己房间
What? You'll have your own room.
不要  我才不要跟你住一起
Uh, no. I am not staying with you.
担心我们孤男寡女  你无法自控吗
Ahh. Worried you can't control yourself when we're alone?
事实上  我不是担心我自己
Actually, it's not me that I'm worried about.
我向你保证  我的动机很纯洁的
I assure you, my intentions are pure.
我们很高兴你再次光临  卡塞尔先生
We're so happy to have you back, Mr. Castle.
我擅自做主把套房布置好了
I've taken the liberty of setting up the suite
-按您喜欢的样子来的  -谢谢
- Just the way you like it. - Thank you.
我预约了7点钟的双人按摩
And I've schedule a couples massage at 7:00.
-很纯洁嘛  -莫瑞斯  你可以把那个取消掉
- Pure, huh? Uh, Maurice, you can go ahead and cancel that,
然后把这些花和香槟撤掉
and get rid of the flowers and the champagne.
我们是来办公事的
We're here to work.
没问题  先生
Very good, sir.
给你的
For you.
谢谢  莫瑞斯
Thank you, Maurice.
上次我来这里的时候
The last time I was here,
我带了一个巴黎的超模  所以他以为你是...
I brought this parisian super model so he thought you--
那不重要  你想要不要选一下房间
It's not important. Would you like to choose your room?
不用了  我想即刻就着手调查
No, I'd like to start the investigation.
我们还没叫客房服务呢
We haven't even ordered room service yet.
卡塞尔  我不是来这享受客房服务的
Castle, I'm not here for room service.
我是来讨回公道的
I'm here for justice.
哇哦  到洛杉矶还没一分钟
Wow. In L.A. For all of a minute,
她已经开始引用恶俗片里的对话了
and already she's spouting cheesy movie dialogue.
肯定是因为这里的空气
Must be something in the air.
这是罗伊的住址吗
This is Royce's place?
这是他驾照上登记的地址
This is the address listed on his driver's license.
我怎么不记得你跟我说过他很有钱
Did I miss the part where you told me he was rich?
没有  他也就勉强度日罢了
No. He was barely scraping by.
-是吗  - 是啊  我是迈克·罗伊的朋友
- Yeah? - Yeah, I'm a friend of Mike Royce's.
到后面来
Come around the back.
杰瑞  我没法帮你  对不起
Jerry, I cannot help you out. I'm sorry.
你只能自己
You gotta go without...
我要挂了
I gotta go.
-你好  -你是吉恩·西蒙斯
- Hello. - Whoa. You're Gene Simmons.
是啊  我是Kiss乐队里那个怪胎
Yeah, I'm that weird guy in Kiss.
是啊  那个长舌头还有其他什么的
Yeah, the guy with the long tongue and everything.
你好啊  这位美女是谁
Hello. Who's this pretty little lady?
我是  我是纽约警局的凯特·贝克特警探
I'm, uh, I'm--I'm detective Kate Beckett, NYPD.
迈克惹上什么麻烦了吗
Is Mike in trouble?
-事实上  他被谋杀了  -太可怕了
- Actually, he was murdered. - Oh, that's terrible.
你是怎么认识他的
How did you know him exactly?
几个月前我有麻烦缠身
Well, I got into trouble a few months back,
罗伊帮我解围  作为回报
and Royce helped me out, I helped him,
我让他住在我的客房
and I've been letting him live in my guest house.
你是说
So you're saying,
他专门帮人解决麻烦吗
he was in the business of helping people in trouble?
他做的不错
He was pretty good at it.
-最近有谁找他解决麻烦吗  -有个女孩
- Was he helping anyone lately? - Well, there was a girl.
她是两天前来的  很正  美艳动人
She came by two days ago. Uh, really beautiful, stunning.
你还记得那女孩的名字吗
Uh, this girl, do you remember her name?
她有落下一张大头照
You know what? She dropped off a head shot.
稍等片刻  我去找找
If you give me a chance, I'll go find it.
谢谢
Thank you.
这太诡异了
This is so weird.
怎么了
What?
我万圣节扮的就是他
I've dressed up as him for Halloween.
我也是
Mm. I did, too.
薇罗特·杨  初涉影坛的性感小妞
Violet Young, a smoking-hot wannabe starlet
她唯一的代表作就是《睡衣派对上的僵尸》
whose only credit is "Slumber Party Zombie".
一个女演员能有什么麻烦
What kind of trouble would an actress be in
能把罗伊吓的要跑路
that would scare Royce into running?
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
上在线影院搜索《睡衣派对上的僵尸》
Pulling up "Slumber Party Zombie" On Netflix.
你干嘛
What are you doing?
我联系下薇罗特的经纪公司
I'm gonna get ahold of Violet's agency,
看能不能找到她
see if I can find out where she is.
-莱恩  怎么样了  -我们运气不错
- Yo, Ryan, what's up? - We got lucky.
孩子们爱在对面大楼里涂鸦乱画
Kids were tagging that building across from the alley,
业主就装了个摄像头
so the owner put up a camera.
凶手现身了
There's our shooter.
他的脸和车牌号都看不到
You can't see his face or the license plate number.
但能看到司机的手臂
But you can see the driver's arm.
黑人  正好和我们的杀手黑白配
A black guy. Ebony to our killer's ivory.
你还有朋友在运输安全管理局吗
You still got that friend at T.S.A.?
有 怎么了
Yeah, why?
或许他们会有凶手
Maybe they'll share surveillance footage
过安检时的监控录像
of the security checkpoint that our shooter went through.
这家伙在城里逗留了六小时  对吧
The guy was in town for six hours, right?
如果他在机场穿的
There's a chance that he's wearing the same clothes
和录像里的是同一套衣服
at the airport that he's wearing in our video.
那样我们就能知道他长什么样子了
Which might get us a look at his face.
薇罗特在齐尼思摄影棚拍广告
So Violet's shooting a commercial at Zenith Studios.
不是吧  那可是拍《希特热浪》的地方
No way. That's where they're shooting "Heat wave".
真是命中注定
Oh, wow. It's kismet.
薇罗特在七号摄影棚拍广告
Violet's commercial shoots on stage seven.
里克·卡塞尔
Rick castle!
真不敢相信  你终于肯来了
I cannot believe we finally got you out here.
托尼  你个抢钱专业户
Tony, you money-grubbing bastard.
电影拍的怎么样了
How's filming?
开什么玩笑  兄弟  超赞的
You kidding me? It's awesome, buddy.
你写多少  我们就拍多少
You keep writing 'em, we'll keep making 'em.
托尼  这位是凯特·贝克特
Tony, I want you to meet Kate Beckett.
妮基·希特的人物原型
This is the inspiration for Nikki Heat.
美女  你这长相足够当演员了
Wow. With your looks, honey, you could be an actress.
我做警察做得挺开心的
I'm completely comfortable being a cop.
我去找薇罗特
I'm gonna go and look for Violet.
-很高兴认识你  -我也是
- It was nice to meet you. - You, too.
-她真辣  -是啊
- She's hot. - Mm.
怪不得书中性爱场面描绘的如此传神
No wonder your sex scenes are so steamy.
我们的妮基·希特扮演者在哪  纳塔莉·罗兹
So, uh, where's our Nikki Heat, Natalie Rhodes?
怎么了
What?
纳塔莉有点个人问题
Natalie's having some personal issues.
什么样的个人问题
What kind of personal issues?
这么说吧  她的药方可能出现了一点混乱
Let's just say, there was a slight mix-up with one of her prescriptions
她在戒毒吗
She's in rehab?
嘿  别说是我说的
Hey, you did not hear that from me.
这二位是饰演莱利和奥乔亚的演员
Oh, there are the actors who play Raley and Ochoa.
-霍维和泰勒  -是霍沃才对
- Herv, Taylor.  - It's Herval.
对  我就是那么叫的
Yeah, that's what I said.
这是原著作者  理查德·卡塞尔
This is your creator--Richard Castle.
哥们  我是你头号粉丝
Yo. Big fan, bro.
谢了  我...
Thanks. I--oh.
我读过你所有的作品
I've read all your books.
如果你有时间  我想和你谈谈我的动机
If you have time, I'd love to talk about my motivation.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我是说  我这个角色的内心世界
I mean, what's my character's inner life?
我为什么选择这么做
Why do I do what I do?
你是个警察  这是你的工作
Ah. You're a cop, so it's your job.
卡塞尔  薇罗特今天没来工作
Castle. Violet didn't show up to work today.
我刚和她经纪人谈过
I just talked to her agent.
他说她没道理缺席工作
He said there's no way she would've missed this commercial.
这是她出名的好机会
This was a huge break for her.
我要了她的地址
I've got her address.
你觉得她有麻烦了
You think she's in trouble?
恩  有可能更糟
Yeah, or worse.
-你们在办案吗  -没错
- You guys on the job? - Yeah, yeah.
你们看起来很有范儿
You guys look great.
他们太诡异了
That is just creepy.
没错
Totally.
你好  美女
Hola, chica.
你在这干嘛
What are you doing here?
我刚在附近经过
I was in the neighborhood.
顺便来看看你从罗伊体内取出的子弹
I thought I'd stop by and see if those bullets
是否可以进行弹道分析了
you pulled out of Royce were ready to go over to ballistics.
我那儿有熟人可以保证立刻做分析
I got a friend there who will make sure they get processed right away.
等等  等一下
Mm. Wait, wait, wait, wait a minute.
你说的"朋友"  是接待处那个大胸贱人吗
Is your "friend" that top-heavy tramp in reception?
你说什么
Hmm? What?
我...我的眼里只有你  我甚至都不...
I--you know I only have eyes for you. I don't even--
我手边锋利的东西很多
Mm-hmm. And you know I have easy access to sharp objects.
见鬼了
What the hell?
这是那些子弹吗
Are those the bullets?
是啊  它们竟然在溶解
Yeah. They're dissolving.
我只听过冰做的子弹
I mean, ice bullets I've heard of.
但是能溶解的子弹也太扯了吧
but dissolving bullets?
薇罗特  薇罗特·杨
Violet? Violet Young?
如果真有溶解子弹  我那"阴谋论网站"上的粉丝
You'd think somebody on my conspiracy web sites
一定会提到的
would've mentioned them.
我觉得薇罗特不在家
I don't think Violet's home.
是啊
Yeah.
这样做好吗
You sure this is okay?
不好  当然不好
No, it is not okay.
实际上是  完全
It is actually, completely...
违法的
illegal.
有人吗
Hello?
薇罗特
Violet?
我没闻到尸臭味啊
I don't smell a dead body.
她不在家
She's not here.
是不在  她在纽约呢
No, she's not. She's in New York.
215号航班
早七点
罗伊也是同一趟航班啊
This was Royce's flight.
这么说他们是一起飞去纽约的
Okay, so they flew together.
他可能知道他们俩有麻烦了
He probably knew that they were in trouble
他为了保护她  带她去纽约避难
and he tried to protect her by taking her to New York.
是谁找她麻烦呢
Protect her from what?
这个吗
Maybe from this?
监视照片
Surveillance photos?
她怎么会有监视照片呢
What would she be doing with surveillance photos?
可能罗伊是她雇佣的私家侦探什么的
Maybe Royce was doing some kind of P.I. work for her.
这人走出来的建筑好眼熟啊
The building this guy is coming out of looks familiar.
她收集了有关柯基犬  冲浪和品酒的文章
She has articles on corgis, on surfing, wine tasting.
这都哪跟哪啊
How does any of this add up?
她可能是在为一个角色做调研呢
Maybe she was researching a role.
那会是什么角色啊
And what role would that be?
而这些跟罗伊又有什么关系呢
And what does any of it have to do with Royce?
声音的力量强迫你
The power of... sound... compels you...
条子  条子  条子
Ccops. Cops. Cops.
拍张照  好了
Photo.. Okay.
搞定  走
Okay, go.
洛杉矶警局
L.A.P.D.!
别动
Don't move.
谢谢  下午好
Thanks. Afternoon.
凯尔·席格  劫案凶杀组
Kyle Seeger, robbery-homicide.
凯尔  这是个误会
Look, Kyle, this is a misunderstanding...
你是说你没撬锁
Meaning you didn't pick the lock
-也没非法闯入民宅吗  -她是说她是纽约警局的
- or illegally enter this house? - Meaning she's NYPD.
我知道你是谁  探长
I know who you are, detective.
我理解你痛失挚友
And while I can appreciate your loss,
但你不能带着你不着调的随从
I can't have you and your offbeat sidekick
在我的地盘肆意妄为  犯下重罪
running around my town committing felonies
以非法的方式寻求正义
in some misguided quest for justice.
你是要逮捕我们吗
Are-are you arresting us?
比那个严重
Oh, much worse.
有人想跟你说句话
Somebody wants to have a word with you.
我开免提了  长官
You're on speaker, sir.
私闯民宅
Breaking into people's houses,
你就这么度假的吗  贝克特
that's your idea of a vacation, Beckett?
-长官  听我解释  我  -不  免开尊口
- Sir. I can explain. I was... - No, you cannot.
你能做的  就是搭下班飞机立马给我回来
What you can do is get your ass on the next plane out.
我们在斯芭果餐厅预订了晚餐
Uh, we have a dinner reservation at Spago.
早上再走行吗
Is the morning okay?
你觉得这事很好笑是不是  卡塞尔
Oh, this is all a big joke to you, isn't it, Castle?
等贝克特被扁去做超市保安时
But when Beckett is working mall security,
做她的跟屁虫就不那么诱人了吧
I guess following her around isn't gonna have quite the same allure.
你们俩  马上回来
Both of you, come home now.
挺尴尬的啊
That was awkward.
要是没有别的事
You know, unless there's something else,
我们就走了
I think we should go now.
还有一件事  你们找到要找的东西了吗
Hey, one last thing. Did you find what you were looking for?
找错房了
Wrong house.
欢迎来洛杉矶一游  探长  现在打道回府吧
Welcome to L.A., detective. Now go home.
-蒙哥马利真会开了你吗  -会的
- Would Montgomery really fire you? - Yeah.
-那我们要回纽约了  -才不呢
- So we're going back to New York. - Hell, no.
莱恩警探
Detective Ryan.
是我  说话方便吗
Hey, it's me. Can you talk?
方便  但是蒙哥马利真的很火大
Yeah, but Montgomery is seriously fired up.
我知道  我需要你帮个忙
Yeah, I know. Look, I need a favor from you,
不过你也可以拒绝我
but you can feel free to say no.
少来了  不管什么我都帮
Oh, come on. Whatever it is, I'm saying yes.
太好了  谢谢
Okay, great. Thanks.
我们认为有人跟随罗恩一起前往纽约的
We think that Royce had company when he traveled to New York.
她叫薇罗特·杨
Her name is Violet Young.
我们认为他遇上的麻烦  她也被卷入其中
We think whatever trouble he was into, she was involved somehow.
-你觉得她还在这吗  -除非麦考利先找到她了
- You think she's still in town? - Unless McCauley got to her first.
她肖像照片后面写着一家纽约的艺校
Her head shot lists an acting school in New York.
她可能在那里有朋友
She might have friends out there.
你能去查查她有没有跟那里的人联络吗
Can you see if she contacted any of them?
好的  我随时通知你进展
You got it. I'll keep you posted.
太好了  谢谢
Great. Thank you.
埃斯波西托查到点东西  贝克特  二号线
Uh, Esposito's got something. Beckett, line two.
还好吗  美女  你的世界天气如何啊
'Sup, girl? How's the weather in your world?
阳光明媚  爽的很呢  你查到什么了
Sunny, chance of ass kicking. What do you got?
凶手的照片  运输安全管理局帮忙找到的
A photo of our killer, courtesy of T.S.A.
我现在就给你发过去
I'm shooting it over to you now.
这就是尼尔·麦考利吗
And that's Neel McCauley?
不管他是谁  他在肯尼迪机场穿的衣服
Well, whoever he is, he wore the exact same clothes at J.F.K.
和小巷摄像头拍到的一样  我们就是这么找到他的
as he did in that alley. That's how we got him.
好吧  虽然不太可能  但是在联邦和本地
Okay, look, this is a long shot, but run facial recognition
-资料库里用面部识别系统查查他  -好的
- through the federal and local databases. - You got it.
-我找到他了  -尼尔·麦考利吗
- I found him. - Neel McCauley?
不是  薇罗特家里照片上那个神秘男子
No. The mystery man from the photo in Violet's place.
我想起在哪儿见过他背后那栋建筑物了
I realized where I'd seen that building he was coming out of before.
是《原始狂怒: 原始复仇》里的坏蛋总部
It was the bad guys' headquarters in "Primal Fury: Primal Vengeance."
所以我上网搜索了一下  然后发现
So did a little internet search, and bam,
那是"北美凯文"的总部
said the lady, found it's the home of Kelvin North America.
搞研发的机构
Some kind of R&D facility.
行政总裁是查尔斯·凯文
The chief executive officer is Charles Kelvin.
猜猜他喜好什么
Guess what his hobbies are.
红酒  柯基犬和冲浪  薇罗特在研究他
"Wine, corgis and surfing." Violet was studying him.
凯文先生
Mr. Kelvin!
Mr. Kelvin.
你助理说我们在这里可以找到你
Your assistant said that we could find you here.
现在是我的冲浪时间
This is my surf hour.
所以不管你有什么事情  等我冲浪回来再说
So whatever you have to say, it can wait till I'm done.
不能等  我是凯特·贝克特探长
No, it can't. I'm Detective Kate Beckett.
这位是理查德·卡塞尔  你认识这个女人吗
This is Richard Castle. Do you recognize this woman?
认识
Sure.
上周五买咖啡排队时遇到了她  我约了她
I met her in line for coffee last Friday, asked her out.
我以为约会进展不错  直到她去了洗手间
Thought the date was going well till she went to the bathroom
再就没回来  问这个干什么
and never came back. What's this all about anyways?
她出事了吗
Something happen to her?
这段录音是怎么回事
Does this recording mean anything to you?
声音的作用会迫使你
The power of... sound... compels you--
-这不是你的声音吗  -那个贱人
- Isn't that your voice? - That bitch.
什么意思
What does that mean?
那句是我们高端保险库的密码
That phrase is the key to our high security vault.
薇罗特一定是在和我约会时
Violet must have pieced it together
录下了我的话然后将其拼凑在一起
from words I said during the date.
我得回办公室了
I gotta get back to the office.
不
No.
-都不见了  -这里原来有什么
- They're gone. - What was in here?
那是保密信息
That's proprietary information.
一颗子弹
A bullet?
我猜这颗是可溶解的
I'm guessing it dissolves.
你怎么知道的
How do you know about those?
-子弹被用在谋杀案中  -上帝啊
- They were used in a murder. - God.
我们研制出这些子弹是为了拿下
We created them to try to land a defense contract
轻型弹药的国防合约
in ultralight ammunition.
这种可溶解属性完全是意外
The dissolving property was a complete accident.
不幸的是  这使得该子弹对军方毫无用处
Unfortunately, it rendered the bullets useless to the military.
是啊  但对有些人来说却大有用处
Yeah, but valuable to someone else.
这他妈的到底是怎么发生的
Now how the hell did this happen?
-有关于薇罗特的好消息  -你找到她了吗
- Good news on Violet. - You found her?
没那么好  但她还活着
Uh... not that good, but she is alive.
至少昨晚她还活着
Or at least she was last night.
找到她的某位前男友
Tracked down an ex of hers
说她昨天出现在他门前  一副吓傻的样子
who said she showed up on his doorstep, scared out of her mind,
说她和罗伊刚从洛杉矶回来
told him she had come out from L.A. with Royce,
但是罗伊失踪了  所以前男友就留她过了夜
but he had disappeared, so the ex let her stay the night.
第二天早上薇罗特不见了  他钱包也不见了
Next morning, Violet was gone, so was his wallet.
他知道她去哪了吗
He know where she was headed?
不  但是两小时后
Uh, no, but two hours later,
一位壮硕  喜欢痛扁别人腰部的
a large African-American gentleman
非裔美国男人出现在他家
with a fondness for kidney punches showed up
问了一模一样的问题
and asked that very same question.
接麦考利的那个司机
The driver who picked up McCauley.
英雄所见略同
That's what I was thinking.
把前男友揍得很惨啊
Worked the ex over pretty good, too.
让他跟素描师合作画头像吧
Let's get him with a sketch artist.
兄弟  早就想到了
Way ahead of you, bro.
看来不只是我们在找薇罗特
Looks like we're not the only ones hunting for Violet.
想象一下  一个年轻天真女演员
Picture this-- a gullible young actress,
极度渴望成名
desperate to make a name for herself.
她在一家俱乐部遇到了该案主谋
She meets our mastermind at a club.
他需要一个漂亮姑娘帮他拿到声音密码
He needs a pretty girl to help him get the voice code.
他告诉薇罗特他是一个制作人并保证
He tells Violet he's a producer, promises to make her famous
只要帮他对朋友搞个恶作剧就会让她出名
if she helps him play a practical joke on a friend.
她直到事后才意识到
She doesn't even realize
她参与了犯罪
that she's participating in a crime until afterwards.
她不能报警  所以她找到了罗伊
She can't call the cops, so she contacts Royce.
但是随后麦考利先生发现了
But then our Mr. McCauley finds out.
罗伊试图扭转局面
And Royce tries to change the game.
他去了纽约  占据地利
He goes to New York-- home field advantage.
典型的  典型的罗伊作风
Classic. Classic Royce.
卡塞尔  我第一次见到他时
I was so in awe of him, Castle.
我太敬畏他了
When I first met him.
我牢牢记住他说的每一个字
I just hung on his every word.
之后  我意识到
And then later, I realized,
他只不过是编故事糊弄我
he was just making up stories to mess with me.
我不敢相信  我从此再也见不到他了
I can't believe that I'm never gonna see him again.
你知道第一见到你时我在想什么吗
You know what I thought when I first met you?
什么
Hmm?
你是我永远无法解读的谜题
That you were a mystery I was never gonna solve.
即使是现在
Even now,
和你朝夕相处
after spending all this time with you,
我
I'm...
我还是惊叹于
I'm still amazed
你深邃的精神力量
at the depths of your strength,
你的心
your heart...
还有你的性感
and your hotness.
你也不赖  卡塞尔
You're not so bad yourself, Castle.
我该回屋了  很晚了
I should go. It's late.
晚安
Good night.
凯特
Kate.
晚安  卡塞尔
Good night, Castle.
某人起得真早
Somebody's up early.
怎么  你连谋杀板都带来了吗
What, did you pack a murder board?
礼宾部送上来的
Concierge.
打了个电话  十分钟就送来了
Called down, and then minutes later, voila.
-莫瑞斯真不错啊  是吧  -确实
- Oh, Maurice is amazing, isn't he? - Yeah.
我打赌就算我要个约柜  他也能搞定
I bet if I ordered the Ark of the Covenant, he'd come through.
你不敢打开吧
Wouldn't you be afraid to open it?
敢啊  它只会消灭纳粹分子
No. It only melts nazis.
那是北美凯文的平面结构图吗
Is that, uh, Kelvin North America?
我正琢磨这起劫案呢
Yeah, I'm trying to figure out this heist.
凯文说最后一次有人进入保险库是在
Kelvin said that the last time that vault was accessed
周二晚上11点46分
11:46 Tuesday night.
那一定就是劫匪
Well, that must be when our thieves
偷走高科技弹药的时候
stole the high-tech ammo.
重达800磅[约363公斤]
800 pounds worth,
他们必须把弹药运到货车卸货处
and they would've had to take it out the loading dock.
但那有个保安值班处
But that guard station there,
我们进去的时候  我记得看见过
I remember seeing that when we went in.
除非有内鬼  要不他们根本不可能
There's no way they could get all that ammo past him
-把弹药运出去  -没错
- without a little insider help. - Exactly.
所以我询问了保安公司  他们说
So I called the security company, and they said that
那天晚上在货车卸货处值班的
the only guard that was stationed at the loading bay
只有一个叫雷吉·维尔士的人
that night was some guy named Reggie Walsh.
我觉得案情越发扑朔迷离了
I feel the plot about to thicken.
是的  他昨天主动辞职了
Yes, he asked to be reassigned the next day.
你约了人吗
Are you expecting anyone?
没有
No.
等等  慢着
Hey, wait, wait, wait. Wait.
席格探长
Detective Seeger.
-卡塞尔先生  -请进
- Mr. Castle. - Do come in.
你们的房间不赖嘛
Wow. Nice digs.
同畅销书作家出游  真是福利颇多啊
It sure pays to travel with a best-selling author, huh?
席格  如果你是来送我们去机场的
Seeger, if you're here to drive us to the airport,
很遗憾我们还没收拾行李呢
We're not packed yet.
我来这是因为一份报告出现在了我的办公桌上
I'm here because a report crossed my desk about a theft
关于北美凯文盗窃案的
at Kelvin North America.
我的脑海里立刻浮现了你们的名字
Your names jumped out at me.
老实交代吧  这起高科技子弹失窃案
Now tell me, what does the theft of high-tech bullets
跟你们调查的谋杀案有什么联系
have to do with your murder investigation?
我们不再调查谋杀案了  不记得了吗
We're not investigating a murder anymore, remember?
我们被调离了
We're off the case.
跟我打马虎眼吗
Are we gonna do that dance?
关于那起失窃案  我们掌握的情况不比你多
Look, we don't know any more about that theft than you do.
但如果我们在去机场的路上
But if we stumble across something
发现了什么线索的话  一定会马上通知你
on our way to the airport, we'll be sure and let you know.
就这么办吧
See that you do.
探长
Detective.
慢走
Good-bye.
你确定隐瞒他是个好主意吗
Are you sure it's such a good idea, cutting him out?
他有可能助我们一臂之力
He might be able to help us.
卡塞尔  席格只在乎那起失窃案
Castle, the only thing Seeger cares about is that robbery,
根本不关心罗伊的谋杀案
not Royce's murder.
我们要做的是去盘问那个保安  雷吉·维尔士
What we need to do is question that guard--Reggie Walsh.
怎么问  你在这根本无法行使警察的权力
How? You're not a cop here, remember?
雷吉又不知道
Reggie doesn't need to know that.
我已经说过了  我对盗窃案一无所知
Like I told you, I don't know anything about a robbery.
得了吧  雷吉  你在撒谎
Gimme a break, Reggie. You're lying.
你这无赖
You're a punk.
下流的混蛋  卑鄙的鼠辈
A dirty skell. A low-down, rat bastard--
伙计们  冷静点
Easy, guys.
对啊  我们都是穿警服的  不是吗
Yeah, I-I mean, we all wear the uniform, right?
是啊  希望你的警服上电视的时候好看点
Yeah, I just hope yours makes you look good on TV.
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
因为分局外的新闻媒体
The news cameras outside of the precinct.
他们就喜欢捕捉嫌疑人被警察铐走的画面
They just love a good perp walk, Reggie.
如果你卷了进来
And if you're mixed up with this, I'm sure
我担保你一定不想被人目睹跟警察说话
you wouldn't want to be seen talking to the cops.
因此出于尊重
So as a courtesy,
我决定用外套让你遮盖一下
I am going to let you cover up with my jacket.
等我们到了审讯室  再把外套拿下来
I wouldn't take it off before we get into the interview room.
因为里面可能会有记者
There might be reporters on the inside.
好吧
Okay.
雷吉  你是个保安
You're a security guard, Reggie.
在监狱里  你是最受压迫的阶层
In prison, you're the lowest of the low.
我还以为是那些娈童的变态
I-I thought that was child molesters.
老兄  你可是个保安啊
Dude, security guard.
你是知道在隆波克他们怎么收拾你这类人的
And you know what they do to guys like you in Lompoc.
不知道
No.
什么  这是一杯拿铁
What? That's... This is a latte.
我只喝柴茶拿铁
Okay, I drink Chai Tea lattes.
你们究竟要跟我工作多久
How long do you have to work for me
才能长记性  或者
until you get that right? Huh? Or maybe--
老实交代  雷吉
Come on, Reggie.
我们都知道那晚你就在货车卸货处
We know you were at the loading bay that night.
好吧  呃...
All right. Um...
有两个人找上我
These two guys came to me.
出价500块要我在午夜的时候出去抽根烟
Offered me 500 bucks to take a cigarette break at midnight.
我之所以答应下来  是因为
The only reason I went along is because saying no
拒绝的话没有好下场
didn't really seem like an option.
是这些人吗
Are these the men?
是  就是他们
Yeah. Yeah.
-他们告知你他们的名字了吗  -没有
- Did they give you their names? - No.
我想起来了  他们离开的时候
Oh, but, uh, when they were walking away,
那个黑人称呼他的同伙甘斯
the black guy called the other guy Ganz.
结束了  伙计们  谢谢大家
All right, guys. Thanks very much.
-这屋我们用完了  -开门喽
- We're done with the room. - Open-do!
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
欢迎光临好莱坞
Welcome to Hollywood.
里克  这场戏绝了
Great scene, Ricky.
你说她是明星级的  一点不假
You said she was a star, and that's right.
我能离开了吗
Does this mean I can leave?
他叫拉塞尔·甘斯  在过去五年间
His name is Russell Ganz. Suspected of pulling off
有好几起人尽皆知的劫案都出自他手
several high-profile heists during the last five years,
其中包括
including the theft
2009年一起军用级电路板失窃案
of military-grade circuit boards in 2009.
甘斯非常有手段并且残暴
Ganz is very smart and very violent.
他数百万美元的劫案使得他
His multimillion-dollar scores have allowed him
过着皇族般的生活  坐拥香车美人
to live like royalty-- fast cars, hot women.
如果找对了买家  比如黑帮或毒枭
Dissolving bullets would be worth a fortune
溶解型子弹能卖一大笔钱
for the right buyer, like a gang or a drug cartel.
甘斯在洛杉矶有地址或熟人吗
Do we have an L.A. address for Ganz or any known associates?
找不到地址
Uh, negative on the address.
而且他的朋友大部分都在坐牢
And it looks like most of his friends are incarcerated.
等等  有一个不是  唐纳德·曼尼斯
Wait. Yeah, here's one that's not. Donald Mannis.
他好像正是追踪薇罗特的那个人
He looks exactly like the guy hunting Violet.
曼尼斯也许能让我们找到甘斯
Okay, Mannis might lead us to Ganz,
把他的照片传给各路人马
so let's get his photo to all the troops.
明白  等下再联系
Got it. I'll get back to you.
我们得快点找到甘斯
We gotta find Ganz fast.
他一旦将那些子弹脱手  就会人间蒸发
Once he fences those bullets, he's gonna disappear.
别担心  这家伙不是爱享受吗
Don't worry. The guy likes the perks of wealth?
有个人正好可以帮我们找到他
I know just the guy to help us find him.
甘斯先生在我们圈子非常有名
Oh, Mr. Ganz is well-known within my network.
他是这个城市五星级酒店的常客
He's a frequent guest at our city's five-star hotels.
知道他现在的确切位置吗
Do you actually know where he is?
在东路一个游泳池边的小屋
At a poolside cabana at the eastway.
打电话谈生意的时候
He enjoys being surrounded by beautiful women
他喜欢被美女围绕着
as he conducts business on the phone, which,
据泳池边一个服务生所说  他正在做这个
according to a poolside waiter, he's doing as we speak.
莫瑞斯  非常感谢  你总给我惊喜
Maurice, thank you very much. You never fail to amaze.
不客气  先生  女士
My pleasure, sir, ma'am.
如果甘斯正在游泳池边谈生意
Okay, so if Ganz is doing business poolside,
那他可能正在寻找子弹的买家
He's probably trying to find a buyer for those bullets.
如果我能证明子弹是他偷的
And if I can put him with those bullets,
我就能证明他杀了罗伊
I can prove he killed Royce.
你不觉得现在该通知洛杉矶警局了吗
Well, don't you think it's time we called the L.A.P.D.?
我有个更好的主意
I think I have a better idea.
可以庆功了
It's time for a celebration.
今晚安排下吧  麦克斯
Set it up for tonight, will you, Max?
好的
Yes, sir.
我很欣赏懂得闪耀登场的女人
I appreciate a woman who knows how to make an entrance.
你住在这个酒店吗
You staying at the hotel?
-不  我来见个人  -出差还是度假
- No, I'm meeting someone. - Business or pleasure?
最好兼而有之
Hopefully a bit of both...
甘斯先生
Mr. Ganz.
我叫罗拉·布莱克  请坐
I'm Lola Black. Please sit.
我能为你做点什么  布莱克小姐
What can I do for you, Ms. Black?
我受托于一个规模小却强有力的
I represent a small but powerful group
哥伦比亚商业集团
of Colombian business interests,
他们得知你有一些
and they understand that you're in possession of some...
特殊商品
unique merchandise.
恐怕你认错人了
I'm afraid you've got me confused with someone else.
我不这么认为
Oh, I don't think so.
纽约的那单生意  那个前警察
That business in New York, that ex-cop?
是个很有效的产品展示
It was a very effective product demonstration.
我出实价  而且我的客户
My offer is serious, and my clients
也不习惯听人说不
are not accustomed to hearing the words "No."
关于那个特殊商品的竞价
Well... The bidding on that particular item
二十分钟前已经结束了
closed about 20 minutes ago.
祝你下次好运
Better luck next time.
等等
Wait, uh...
二百万
$2 million.
我可以一小时内拿来
I-I can have it here within an hour.
说实话  我很佩服你的美人计
I'm impressed, actually, the way you lured me in.
差点让我上钩
You had me guessing there for a second.
-这话什么意思  -意思是你是个条子
- What's that supposed to mean? - It means you're a cop.
你是我这么久以来见过的
You're the hottest thing I've seen
重案组警察里最性感的
come out of major crimes in quite some time.
但你有点心太急  有点嫩
But you're a little too eager, a little green.
幸会  罗拉
Nice meeting you, Lola.
天啊  卡塞尔
oh, god, Castle.
出什么事了
So what happened?
我试图不让他看见你
Ow! I was trying to keep him from seeing you,
结果逼得太紧  被他识破了
and so I pushed too hard, and he made me.
他说我嫩  卡塞尔你到底在干嘛
He called me green, Castle. What the hell were you doing?
我看到他的手机在小屋
I saw his phone in the cabana.
-心想值得冒个险  -你拿了他的手机吗
- I thought it was worth the risk. - You took his phone?
没有  我把他最近的通话记录拍下来了
No! No, I took a picture of his recent call list.
什么  在哪儿
What? Where is it?
-别戳我  -戳你干嘛  想亲你呢
- Don't--don't poke me. - Poke you? I want to kiss you.
我们得查查这些号码
Okay, we need to run down these numbers,
看看这里面有没有甘斯的买家
see if we can trace one of them to Ganz's buyer.
那现在可以打电话给席格了吗
Okay, now can we call Seeger?
先生们  薇罗特·杨找的怎样了
Gentlemen, where are we with Violet Young?
我刚跟他母亲通完电话
I just got off the phone with her mother.
她说薇罗特有个室友
She said she remembers Violet having a roommate
住在运河大街附近
who lives near Canal Street.
我们正准备去那儿
Yeah, we're gonna head over there
看看薇罗特是否找过她
and see if Violet reached out to her.
-有消息通知我  -好
- Well, let me know. - Yeah, right.
有贝克特的消息吗
Hey, you heard from Beckett?
-没有  -我也没有
-No, sir. - Yeah, me neither.
她一直不接电话
She's not answering her cell.
她可能在飞机上
Maybe she's airborne.
是啊  难怪手机关机了
Uh-huh. Yeah, that would explain her phone being turned off.
我想看看你俩谁是最蹩脚的骗子
You know, I'm trying to decide who is the worse liar,
你还是他
him or you.
去找薇罗特·杨吧
Go find Violet Young.
帮贝克特好好解决这事  好吗
Help beckett put this thing to bed, all right?
-遵命  -这就行动
- Yes, sir. - Right on.
-你好 席格警... -打住
-Hey, Detective see-- - Hey.
你在我的地盘上撒野  还叫我帮忙吗
You run wild in my city, then you call me for a favor?
我得说探长  你脸皮真是够厚的
You got a lot of nerve, detective. I'll give you that.
我们是在帮你斩奸除恶
Hey, we're trying to get a vicious criminal off of your streets.
有兴趣收下这个浴袍吗
Hey, can I interest you in one of these robes?
在你拒绝之前  感受一下这有多柔软
Before you say no, feel how soft this is.
不了  谢谢
No, thank you.
我们现在目标一致
Look, we're all on the same team now,
为什么一口气解决这案子
so why don't we just get this done with?
得按我的方式才行
As long as it gets done my way.
没问题  你查出什么了
Fine. What do you got?
甘斯使用的是一次性电话
Well, Ganz's phone is a burner,
大部分他拨通的号码也是
and so are most of the numbers he called.
就是说查不到买家身份
Which means you didn't get the buyer's I.D.
我们跟踪到了
We did manage to trace
其中一通打给纽约的电话
one of the burners he called to new york city.
曼尼斯  他是甘斯的同伙
Mannis. That's Ganz's partner.
我打赌甘斯打给他是要问
I bet Ganz was calling to ask
为什么薇罗特·杨还活着
why the hell Violet Young was still alive.
你查到曼尼斯的地址了吗
Did you happen to get a location on Mannis' phone?
只知道在曼哈顿
Just that it's in Manhattan.
好的  我们打过去激怒他
Okay. So let's call him, rile him up a bit.
怎么激怒他
Rile him up how?
我告诉他我见过甘斯了
I'll tell him I met Ganz.
甘斯将不会给他分成
Ganz was gonna cut him out of the deal.
-曼尼斯事情没办到位  -曼尼斯一生气
- Mannis wasn't pulling his weight. - Mannis gets pissed,
打给甘斯  或许他们其中一个
he calls Ganz, maybe one of them
会不小心说出
lets something slip about the
-交易的地点  -我们就会听到了
- location of the exchange. - And we'll be listening.
很好  我去申请授权令
Good. I'll try and get a warrant.
你真难找  薇罗特
You're a hard girl to find, Violet.
我知道逃跑是不对的
I know it was wrong to run,
但我害怕去自首
but I was afraid to go to the cops.
我从没想过要伤害罗伊
I never meant for Royce to get hurt.
我们回局里吧  薇罗特
Well, let's just get back to the station, Violet.
-我们可以协商一下  好吗  -走吧
- We can work it out, all right? - Let's go.
有枪
Gun!
趴下  趴下  趴下
Down! Down! Down!
你还好吗
You okay?
-是的  你呢  -没事
- Yeah. You? - Yeah.
-你呢  -我没事
- You okay? - Yeah.
在这里等着  好吗
Wait right here, all right?
埃斯波西托
Esposito?
贝克特
Beckett?
你和曼尼斯在一起吗
Are you with Mannis?
是的  我射伤了他
Yeah. I just shot him.
你打给他做什么
Why are you calling him?
我们要知道甘斯售卖子弹的
Look, we need to know where and when
时间地点
Ganz is selling those bullets.
唐  交易在哪里进行
Don, where's the deal going down?
-我受伤了  叫救护车  -我的搭档正在处理
- I'm hit man. Call an ambulance. Well, my partner's on that.
9-1  然后是什么呢
9-1--what-- what come after that one?
-我很痛  伙计  -你完蛋了  曼尼斯
- I'm in pain here, man! - It's over, Mannis.
如果你把交易地点告诉我们
If you give us the meet location,
我会跟洛杉矶的地检官说你很合作
I'll tell the D.A. in L.A. that you cooperated.
好吧  我告诉你
Aah! I'll tell you.
六点钟在圣塔莫妮卡码头
Santa Monica pier! 6:00!
-快叫救护车  -是谁杀了罗伊
- Now call an ambulance! - Who shot Royce?
是甘斯
It was Ganz.
-听到了吗  -是的  都听到了  谢谢
- You get that? - Yeah, we got it. Thanks.
得赶去圣塔莫妮卡码头
Gotta get to Santa Monica pier.
还差一刻就到六点了
It's quarter of 6:00 now.
这是我们逮捕甘斯的最后机会
This is gonna be our last chance to get Ganz.
好的  出发吧
Okay. Let's roll.
洛杉矶警局  不许动
L.A.P.D. Freeze.
把箱子放下  把箱子放下
Put the case down. Put the case down.
双手抱头
Get hands behind your head.
货车里的人  警察  双手伸出窗外
You in the van! Police. Both hands out the window.
打开门  慢慢出来
Open the door. Get out slow.
慢点
Slowly.
面向货车
Up against the van.
Up against the van!
把手给我
Give me your hand.
他在哪里  甘斯在哪
Where is he? Where's Ganz?
他在哪里
Aah! Where is he?
找到了
Bingo.
贝克特去哪了
Where did Beckett go?
警察  站住
Police! Stop!
我就知道你是警察
I knew you were a cop.
我是纽约警局的凯特·贝克特探长
My name is Detective Kate Beckett, NYPD.
迈克·罗伊是我的朋友
Michael Royce was my friend.
你射杀了他
You shot him
然后把他像垃圾似的丢在巷子里
and you left him in an alley like a piece of garbage.
把这当做是应得的惩罚吧
Consider this poetic justice.
他说过我会遭受地狱般追缉
He said something about hell raining down on me.
我没想过地狱会如你这般美丽
I never imagined hell looked like you.
凯特
Kate!
拉塞尔·甘斯  你因涉嫌
Russell Ganz, you are under arrest
谋杀迈克·罗伊被逮捕了
for the murder of Michael Royce.
你还好吧
You okay?
是的
Yeah.
当时你是不是差点就对甘斯开枪了
So how close did you come...with Ganz.
我们回去吧  卡塞尔
Let's go home, Castle.
现在说到重点了  丫头
"And now for the hard part, kid.
很明显你和卡塞尔互相吸引
"It's clear that you and Castle have something real,
而你在极力挣扎
"And you're fighting it.
但相信我
"But trust me,
把工作看得比感情重要
"putting the job ahead of your heart
是个错误
"is a mistake.
冒险才是我们活着的意义所在
"Risking our hearts is why we're alive.
人生最令人悔恨的事就是  回忆往昔
"The last thing you want is to look back on your life
心想...
"and wonder...
若是当初
if only."